A Finding Aid to the Duane Hanson Papers, 1935-2006, in the Archives of American Art aaa.hansduan
Archives of American Art
Duane Hanson papers
1935-2006
aaa.hansduan
Archives of American Art
12.9 Linear feet
The papers of Florida realist sculptor Duane Hanson date from 1935-2006 and measure 12.9 linear feet. Hanson's career is documented through biographical information, personal business records, correspondence, subject files, artwork, writings, printed materials, and photographs. There are numerous letters from the O.K. Harris Gallery and Ivan Karp, Dr. Martin Bush at Witchita State University, and Dewey Hanson.
Hanson, Duane, 1925-1996
Related Archival Materials note
The Archives of American Art also holds an oral history interview with Duane Hanson conducted on 1989 August 23-24 by Liza Kirwin.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Duane Hanson's widow, Wesla Hanson, donated his papers in two accretions in 1997 and 2006. Additions are expected.
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original papers requires an appointment. Use of archival audiovisual recordings with no duplicate access copy requires advance notice.
Arrangement note
The collection is arranged as 8 series.
Series 1: Biographical Material 1978-1994 (Box 1; 0.6 linear feet)
Series 2: Personal Business records, circa 1960s-1996 (Box 1-2; 0.5 linear feet)
Series 3: Correspondence, 1963-2006 (Box 2-8; 5.8 linear feet)
Series 4: Subject Files, 1935-1996 (Box 8-9; 1.1 linear feet)
Series 5: Writings and Notes, 1970-1988 (Box 9; 0.2 linear feet)
Series 6: Artwork, circa 1980-circa 1984 (Box 9; 0.3 linear feet)
Series 7: Printed Material, 1958-1994 (Box 9-14; 4.0 linear feet)
Series 8: Photographs, 1978-1990 (Box 14; 0.1 linear feet)
Biographical/Historical note
Sculptor and educator Duane Hanson (1925-1996) spent most of his career in South Florida and is best known for his hyper-realist sculptures of people. Duane Hanson was born January 17, 1925 in Alexandria, Minnesota. His family later moved to Parkers Prairie, Minnesota where he created his first sculpture in wood at the age of 13. He graduated from Macalester College in St. Paul, Minnesota and completed his education with an MFA from the Cranbrook Academy of Art in Michigan. During school and after, Hanson created realistic and grotesque sculptures of taboo subjects and other sculptures depicting physically violent occurrences.
In 1962, Hanson accepted a teaching position at Oglethorpe University in Atlanta, Georgia where he remained for three years. At Oglethorpe, Hanson received grant funds to create his most well-known works out of resin and fiberglass. He moved to South Florida in 1965, where he continued to sculpt life-size human forms with detailed features and accessories.
Art dealer Ivan Karp at O.K. Harris Gallery took an interest in the works and represented Hanson, who moved to New York City to continue his career. He exhibited at numerous solo exhibitions in the United States and Germany. In 1973, Hanson returned to South Florida where he would remain for the duration of his life. His retained the national spotlight, however, and was very active in the Florida art scene. He was named Florida Ambassador of the Arts in 1983. Duane Hanson married his second wife, Wesla in 1968, with whom he had two children. Also, he had two children from a previous marriage which ended in divorce. Hanson died of cancer in January of 1996.
Scope and Contents note
The papers of Florida realist sculptor Duane Hanson date from 1935-2006 and measure 12.9 linear feet. Hanson's career is documented through biographical information, personal business records, correspondence, subject files, artwork, writings, printed materials, and photographs. There are numerous letters from the O.K. Harris Gallery and Ivan Karp, Dr. Martin Bush at Witchita State University, and Dewey Hanson.
The bulk of the collection consists of correspondence and includes personal letters, fan mail, and correspondence with museums, galleries, universities, friends, and colleagues. Subject files also include scattered correspondence but typically contain printed materials and scattered business records. There is a slight overlap between the correspondence files and the subject files.
Biographical materials include a guestbook spanning 1978-1994 from many exhibitions. Also found are four videos, mostly of Hanson's television appearances and exhibitions. Personal business records contain loan records, damage reports, and expense records. Scattered writings include statements by Hanson about his artwork. Also found within the papers is one sketchbook and a few loose sketches. Printed materials largely consist of clipping files and exhibition catalogs. There are photographs are of Duane Hanson and his father Dewey, and of Hanson depicted with various works of art, as well as slides.
Bush, Martin, Dr.; Hanson, Dewey; Karp, Ivan C., 1926-; O.K. Harris Gallery. (New York, N.Y.); Sculptors--Florida; Sketchbooks; Sketches; Video recordings; Visitors' books
- Biographical Materials, 1978-1994; Series 1; 0.6 Linear feet Box 1
  Scope and Contents note
  Scattered biographical materials include resumes, an exhibition guestbook spanning the years 1978-1994, and xerox copies of original geneological documents. Also found here are four videos, mostly of Hanson's television appearances and exhibitions.
  Arrangement note
  This series has been minimally processed. Audio visual materials have been rehoused if needed, but have not been viewed or described.
  - Awards, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Biographical Sketches and Resumes, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Geneological Documents, 1987-circa 1990 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
    File contains xerox copies of original geneological materials
  - Name Plate, circa 1990s (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Guest Book, 1978-1994 (Box 1, Box-folder 6)
  - Mary Wallace: Duane Hanson's Fundraiser, Museum of Contemporary Art, 1983; 1 Videocassettes (U-matic) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Duane Hanson with John Chancellor, NBC Nightly News, circa 1980; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) 1 VHS Tape, 2:37:28 minutes (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Fenster aus Berlin, Ausstellung" Duane Hanson, circa 1990; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Duane Hanson, Tom Snyder Show and Andy Warhol, Today Show, circa 1980s; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Personal Business records, circa 1960s-1996; Series 2; 0.8 Linear feet Boxes 1-2
  Personal business records include address books, legal documents, consent forms, copyright information, recepits for freight, invoices, and expense records, a list of works in the Duane Hanson Collection, the Fort Lauderdale Museum Board records, and records relating to donations and loans. Of note are reports of damage and repairs made to Hanson's sculptures. Also found are letters of recommendation written by Hanson for others.
  - Address Books, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Includes family histories and trees
  - Business Card and Design, circa 1980s (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Business Investment Ideas, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Contracts, 1984-1995 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Consent Forms, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Copyright Registration, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Crating and Freighting, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Duane Hanson Collection, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Fort Lauderdale Museum Board, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - General Financial Records, 1973-1996 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Interviews, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Invoice, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Lease, 1978-1990 (Box 1, Folder 23-24)
  - Ledger, 1979-1985 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Ledger, Bookkeeping, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Letters of Recommendation, for Others, 1986-1989 (Box 1, Folder 27-28)
  - Loan and Donation Records, 1979-1996 (Box 1, Folder 29-37)
  - Receipts and Expenses, 1983-1996 (Box 2, Folder 1-7)
  - Rentals, Land, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Repairs, to Works of Art, 1982-1984 (Box 2, Folder 9-11)
  - Security Agreement, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Shipping Records, 1989-1995 (Box 2, Folder 13-14)
  - Tuition for Maja Hanson, R.I.S.D., 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, 1963-2006; Series 3; 5.8 Linear feet Boxes 2-8
  The majority of correspondence consists of letters to Hanson, however there are scattered drafts of responses. There are circa 20 folders of personal correspondence. Professional correspondence discusses specific works of art, exhibitions, and Hanson's activities at local schools, museums, and universities. There are a significant number of letters from Harry Abrams, Martin Bush, Cranbrook, Fort Lauderdale Museum of Art, Frederick R. Weisman Co., O. K. Harris Gallery and Ivan Karp, Helander Gallery, Norton Gallery, and Hannes Von Gosselin. There is also correspondence about events, exhibitions, and travel.
  Personal correspondence is arranged chronologically. Professional correspondence is arranged alphabetically by either name of correspondent, or by topic. For the most part Hanson's original file order and folder titles have been maintained. Generally, items within the folders have not been further arranged into chronological order.
  - Personal Correspondence, 1973-1985 (Box 2, Folder 16-29)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1986-1993 (Box 3, Folder 1-7)
  - General Correspondence, 1972-1995 (Box 3, Folder 8-29)
  - Fan Mail, 1973-1977 (Box 3, Folder 30-33)
  - Fan Mail, 1978-1993 (Box 4, Folder 1-14)
  - Abrams, Harry, 1983-1988 (Box 4, Folder 15-18)
  - Alaska, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Alexandria Museum (Louisiana), 1986 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - American Artist, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Amherst College, (Sweeny, Robert), 1986 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Arts Legislation, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Archives of American Art, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Arkansas State University, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Art in Public Places, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Art League, Bradenton, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Art Life, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Auckland, New Zealand, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 29-30)
  - Australia, 1978-1988 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Barcheski, R., 1977-1979 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - B. L. Stryker TV Show, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Berlin, 1990s (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Birthday Cards, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Black, Carolyn, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Boise Gallery of Art, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Books, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Broward Art Guild Magazine, 1986-1988 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Buchsteiner, Thomas, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Bush, Martin, 1975-1996 (Box 4, Folder 44-61)
  - California, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Canada, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Children's Television Workshop, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - China, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Collectors, 1975-1991 (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
  - Colleges and Universities, 1975-1990 (Box 5, Folder 7-18)
  - Columbia Museum, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Conant, Howard, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Cranbrook Academy of Art, 1978-1994 (Box 5, Folder 21-32)
  - David Letterman Show, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Davy, Mike, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Des Moines Art Center, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Dollars for Scholars, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Eberhardt, Angelika, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Eckes-Chantre, Heidi, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Edwin A. Ulrich Museum of Art, Wichita State University, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Elizabeth Galasso Fine Art Leasing, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Ellison, Jessie, 1982-1985
    Includes poetry
  - England, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Eve Mannes Gallery, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Florida Department of State, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Florida State University, Tallahassee, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Floridanica, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Fort Lauderdale Museum of Art, 1986-1990 (Box 5, Folder 47-48)
  - Fort Worth Museum of Modern Art, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Frederick R. Weisman, Co., 1986-1994 (Box 5, Folder 50-51)
  - Frostburg College, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Frudakis, Zenos, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Georgia Art Museum, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Germany, 1973-1978 (Box 5, Folder 55-59)
  - Grigsby, Emily, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Harris, O.K., 1968-1991 (Box 5, Folder 61-66)
    and Ivan Karp
  - Hawaii, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - Heidelberg, 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - Helander Gallery, 1985-1989 (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - "Help-Outs", 1978-1985 (Box 5, Folder 70-71)
  - Hirschhorn Museum, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - Hochstaetter, Rosalie, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 73)
  - Honolulu Academy of Arts, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 74)
  - Holiday Cards (Various), 1981 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Honors and Awards, 1985-1995 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Horizon, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Institut of Kulturaustausch, 1990s (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - International Platform Association, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - International Sculpture Center, 1985-1986 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Interviews, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 7-9)
  - Ireland, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Ishoy, Roy, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Itawamba Jr. College, Fulton, Mass., 1981 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Japan, 1988-1995 (Box 6, Folder 13-16)
  - Kurland/Summers Gallery, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - L. A. Salomon and Brothers, Inc., 1978 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - La Jolla Museum, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Laguna Beach Museum of Art, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Lectures, 1982-1987 (Box 6, Folder 21-22)
  - Lembark, Connie, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Letters from 1st Grade Class, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Levison Kane Gallery, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Lipman, Jean, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - LIvingstone, Marco, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Lowe Art Museum, 1985-1988 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Ludwig Museum, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - MacAlester College, 1985-1990 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Marx, Jeffrey (Helander Gallery), 1984-1990 (Box 6, Folder 32-33)
  - McBride, Anita, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - McLean, Richard, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Menkin, Joan, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Metzenbaum, Senator Howard, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Mikus, Eleanor, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Millesgarden, Sweden, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Montreal, Canada, 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Montreal Museum of Art, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Morgan, Myra, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Museums and Galleries (Florida, International, and National), 1977-1990 (Box 6, Folder 43-56)
  - Museums and Galleries (Florida, International, National), 1980-1991 (Box 7, Folder 1-9)
  - National Endowment for the Arts, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - National Galleries of Scotland, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - National Trust for Historic Preservation, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Neuendorf, Hans, 1993-1994 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - New York City, 1974-1988 (Box 7, Folder 14-16)
  - New York Prosthetic Center, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - New York University, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - New Zealand Art Museum, 1988-1989 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - New Zealand Show, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Norton Gallery, 1985-1995 (Box 7, Folder 21-22)
  - Ohio Art Education Association, 1987-1988 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Orlando Airport, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Orlando Museum of Art, 1986-1988 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Palm Beach County Council of the Arts, 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts, 1977-1990 (Box 7, Folder 27-29)
  - People Magazine, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Philadelphia Museum Council, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Philbrook Museum of Art, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Photography, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Plantation Junior Woman's Club, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Pleeter, Louis, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Pollock, Lewis, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Postcards, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Proposals for Documentaries and Books, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Requests for Recommendations, Reproductions, and Loans, 1980-1983 (Box 7, Folder 39-41)
  - Reporters and Critics, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Rhode Island School of Design, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Ringling Museum of Art, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Rubin, Sherry, 1978-1979 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Ruhrberg, Karl, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Russ, Irina (Reuss), 1991 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Russia, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Scholastic, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Schools, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Seattle, Washington, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Shiftung Haus der Geschichte, 1993-1994 (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Shimbun, Asahi, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Shippenburg University, 1987-1988 (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Sidney Janis Gallery, 1973, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Silverman, Gilbert, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Sinclair Lewis Foundation, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Smithsonian, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Snyder, David, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - South Carolina State Museum, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Southeastern Center for Contemporary Art, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Strickland, Barbara, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - Sun-Tattler, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Sweden and Finland, 1973-1991 (Box 7, Folder 64-65)
  - Talks, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 66)
  - Teixeira, Maria Teresa, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 67)
  - Théberge, Pierre, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 68)
  - Tucson Museum of Art, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 69)
  - University of Arizona, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 70)
  - University of California, Berkeley, 1977, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 71)
  - University of Houston, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 72)
  - University of Miami, 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 73)
  - University of South Florida, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 74)
  - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 75)
  - Von Gosselin, Anya, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 76)
  - Von Gosselin, Hannes, 1990-1991 (Box 7, Folder 77-78)
  - Wallace, M., 1984 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Weber, Karl, 1990s (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1977-1989 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - WPBT Channel 2, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Yamaoaka, Nagatomo, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Wesla Hanson's Correspondence, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Subject Files, 1935-1996; Series 4; 1.1 Linear feet Boxes 8-9
  The arrangement of these files into a separate series follows Hanson's original order. Original folder titles have also been maintained. Researchers should note that this is some overlap between the subject files and the correspondence files.
  Generally, subject files consist of printed materials and scattered correspondence or business records relating to specific exhibitions, prizes or awards, and projects. Also found are files regarding supplies used by Hanson for his sculptures, including artificial eyes, hair, and other materials.
  - Airport Project, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Bahn Commission, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Body Measurement, circa 1970s (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Bronze Casting Co. and Meisne & Co. Inc., 1984 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Brown University and Rhode Island School of Design Show, 1990-1991 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Chemicals, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Commission, 1979-1988 (Box 8, Folder 13-14)
  - Cooper City High School, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Cowboy Project, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Current Exhibitions, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Department of State, Southwestern Bell, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Deutscher Akademischer Austauschdienst, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Du Pont, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Eyes, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - F.A.E.A. Evaluation Forms, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - The Florida Prize, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - "for Archives", 1984-1996 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Fort Lauderdale Museum of Art, 1990s (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Fort Worth Exhibit, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Foundaries, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Games, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Hair Prices, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Hanson, Dewey, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Idea Photos (Airport and Japan), 1975 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Japanese Newspaper, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Lectures and Panels, 1978-1984 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - MacAlester Class, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    Includes letter from Joan Mondale
  - Materials and Supplies, 1977-1990 (Box 8, Folder 35-36)
  - Memmel, Bob, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Milles Garden, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Mold Making Materials, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Montreal Exhibit, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - New Materials, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Old Whitney Shows, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Orlando Airport Commission, circa 1990 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Painting Bronze Sculpture, circa 1980 (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Parkers Prairie, Minnesota, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Publications, 1978-1995 (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Quebec, Canada, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Repairs, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Rodeo, Tucson, Arizona, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Rotary Vacuum Pump and Fan, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Russia Show, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Sculpture House, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Sculpture Maintenance and Preservations, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Studio Assistants and Models, circa 1986 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Talks and Demonstrations, 1984-1985 (Box 9, Folder 3-4)
  - Taxidermy, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - To Tell the Truth, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Tokyo Shows, 1984-1985 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Travels, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - TV and Published Interviews, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Videos, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Vinyls, circa 1978 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Warhol, Andy, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Waxes, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Who's Who in America, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - World Design Exposition Association, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Young, Doug, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Youth Leadership, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 17)
- Writings and Notes, 1970-1988; Series 5; 0.2 Linear feet Box 9
  There are scattered writings and notes by and about Duane Hanson. Of particular interest are his personal statements on works and exhibitions.
  - List of One-Man Exhibitions, circa 1979 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Statement on Stop Crime, circa 1978 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Statements on Work, 1970-1984 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Facing Reality: The Art of Duane Hanson by Marco Livingstone, circa 1980 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Interview Form, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Art Notes, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Book with Harry Abrams, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Statements on Techniques, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Notes and Addresses, 1980-1985 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Lectures, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - German Text on Hanson by Karl Ruhrberg, circa 1984 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Notepad, circa 1980s (Box 9, Folder 29)
- Artwork, circa 1980-circa 1984; Series 6; 0.3 Linear feet Box 9
  There is one sketchbook, loose sketches, and a pencil covered in paint.
  - Sketchbook, circa 1980s (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Sketches, circa 1980 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Pencil with Paint, circa 1984 (Box 9, Folder 32)
- Printed Material, 1958-1994; Series 7; 4 Linear feet Boxes 9-14, 15
  Printed materials include newspaper and magazine clippings, and various exhibition announcements and catalogs. There is a file of critical reviews from Worpswede, Germany for Hanson's first exhibition in that country.
  - Clipping Files, 1963-1980 (Box 9, Folder 33-43)
  - Clipping Files, 1981-1988 (Box 10, Folder 1-15)
  - Clipping Files, 1977-1992 (Box 11, Folder 1-19)
  - Clippings, circa 1960s-1990s (Box 11, Folder 20-26)
  - Clippings, 1970s-1990 (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
  - Press Clipping Booklets, circa 1990 (Box 12, Folder 3-4)
  - Sun-Tattler Newspaper, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1974-1994 (Box 12, Folder 6-7)
  - Announcements, 1990s (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Poster, circa 1990s (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - N.A.E.A. Conference, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Interview, 1983 May (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Programs, 1985-1987 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Fort Lauderdale Museum of Art, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Rolodex, circa 1980 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Farm Bulletins, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Sculptor Newsletters, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - German, circa 1989 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - L.A. Times Magazine, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Worpswede, Germany, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Magazines, 1970s-1990s (Box 12, Folder 20-25)